【  -=THE LAST FANTASY=- 荣誉出品  】
【-=TLF字幕组=- 翻译：马田的心事      校对：揽星】
诚邀字幕翻译、做轴人员 请邮件联系tlf_subteam@hotmail.com
原来你在这儿
There you are.
我找你好久了
I've been looking for you.
见过我的另一只鞋吗？
Have you seen my other shoe?
怎么啦？
What?
为什么那样看着我？
Why are you looking at me like that?
去尿尿
Go potty.
史考特
Scotty.
听话，史考特
Come on, boy. Scotty.
去尿尿，史考特
Go potty, Scotty.
别用那种眼神看我
Don't look at me like that.
恩？
Yes?
美好一天从运动开始，对吧？
Great way to start the day, right?
跑得我快吐了
I think I'm gonna puke.
老妈说你上周约会去了，怎么样？
Mom said you went on a date last week.How'd it go?
还成
It was okay.
成功的和妞上床了吗？
"Okay" as in you got laid?
-  哈利- 干嘛
-Harry.-What?
她听不见
She can't hear you.
难道你这辈子不想再做爱了吗？
Don't you wanna have sex,like, ever again in your life?
当然想，但我不是情场高手
Yes. I just don't think that I'm the dating type.
妞们想跟我上床的唯一原因是高中时看过我的书
Girls only wanna sleep with me because they read my book in high school.
所以呢？
So?
所以她们对我没兴趣
So they're not interested in me.
对我的一些想法感兴趣罢了
They're interested in some idea of me.
那你应该长期健身，那样她们就会想要你了
That's why you should keep working out.That way, they'll want you for your body.
健身的意义是什么？
What does this thing even do?
让你变成“艳遇之神”
It turns you into a god.
继续练
Keep going.
昨晚我做了个怪梦
Hey, I had a weird dream last night.
梦见个女孩，她…
There was this girl and she was...
长什么样？
What'd she look like?
我虚构的一个平凡女孩
Just a normal girl.Just a girl I made up.
后来怎么了？
Well, what happened?
她只是跟我说了几句话
She just talked to me.
真郁闷
That's depressing.
实际上感觉不错
Actually, it was really nice.
开玩笑吗？你连做梦都泡不到妞？那真是…
Seriously? You don't even get laid in your dreams? That's...
悲催了
That's just sad.
新书写的怎么样了？
Hey, how's the new book coming along?
不知道，我有个好想法，本来打算写我爸
I don't know. I get a good idea,like why don't I write about my dad?
后来又觉得这想法太蠢了
And then, bam, I start thinking that it's the stupidest thing ever.
没人想读“他对我失望透顶
Who wants to read about,"He was disappointed in me...
之类的故事
...blah, blah, blah"?
而且，我现在对史考特又爱又恨
Also, I'm feeling ambivalent about Scotty.
它流口水，乱咬东西
Yeah, he slobbers. He chews things.
撒尿像个姑娘似的，我感觉很尴尬
He pees like a girl, which makes me feel inadequate.
它喜欢出门遛遛，我也得跟着出去，这就是我没法写书的原因
He needs to go outside a lot, breaks up my day. That's why I'm not writing.
你认为这是你没法动笔的原因吗？
Do you think that's why you're not writing?
- 不是 - 那是什么原因呢？
- No. - Why do think you're not writing?
能把鲍比给我吗？
Can I have Bobby now?
- 你现在需要鲍比吗？ - 对
- Do you need Bobby now? - Yes.
卡尔文…
Calvin...
你最后一次见朋友是什么时候？
...when's the last time you saw a friend?
昨天见了哈利
Harry. Yesterday.
不，除了你哥之外的其他人
No, no.Someone other than your brother.
你把鲍比给过其他病人吗？
Uh, have you been giving Bobby to your other patients?
没，鲍比是你专属的
No, Bobby is just for you.
- 它有股怪味 - 卡尔文
- Because he smells weird. - Calvin...
当你决定和史考特一起生活的时候，我们怎么说来着？
...when you were deciding to get Scotty, what did we talk about?
你说你的愿望是什么来着？你还记得吗？
What did you say your hopes were?Do you remember?
它能让我融入社交圈
That he would help me meet people.
请大声点
A little louder, please?
它会成为我的好朋友，我们会一起散步游玩
That he would be awesome and we'd take hikes and stuff.
人们会停下来逗它，这样我就能遇见陌生人
And people would stop to pet him,and I would meet them.
但史考特害怕陌生人的接近
But Scotty gets scared when people try to pet him.
你感到尴尬吗？
Does that embarrass you?
- 不 - 我给你布置个写作任务
- No. - I wanna give you a writing assignment.
- 我无法写 - 好吧
I can't write. Okay.
就给我一个人看
This would just be for me.
写篇文章描述一个人
I'd like you to write a page...
这个人尽管看到了史考特流口水也好，有恐惧症也好
...about someone who sees Scotty all slobbery and scared...
依然喜欢真实的史考特
...and likes him anyway,just the way he is.
你觉得能为我完成吗？
You think you could do that for me?
写的差也行？
Can it be bad?
即使写的再差我也喜欢
I'd like it to be very bad.
我第一次见卡尔文时他19岁
I first met Calvin when he was 19 years old.
当时他已经位居
And he'd already been at the top...
纽约时报畅销书作者排行榜第一位长达几个月了
...of The New York Times Best Seller list, uh, for several months.
我当时在想
And I remember thinking:
“这孩子到底是谁？”
"Who the fuck is this kid?
我要怎样才能时光倒流成为他那样的人呢？
And, uh, how can I go back in time and be him?"
一个下巴上仍长着青春痘的辍学高中生
A high-school dropout with acne still on his chin...
却写出了极有可能成为美国经典小说的作品
...gave us what may very well become a classic American novel.
自此以后，我们都爱上了他的短篇小说
Since then, of course,we've all enjoyed his short stories...
也包括去年的中篇小说“饕餮盛宴”
...uh, including last year's novella,Breakfast for Dinner.
但只有当我静下心来重读他的作品时
But it was only when I sat down and reread his novel...
精美的十周年纪念版现已上市
...now available in a beautiful 10th anniversary edition...
我才意识到卡尔文·威尔菲尔兹有多么优秀
...that, uh, I realized just how good a writer Calvin Weir-Fields is.
今生有他，实属幸运
We are lucky to have him around.
女士们，先生们，有请卡尔文·威尔菲尔兹
Ladies and gentlemen,Calvin Weir-Fields.
- 无与伦比，太棒了 - 谢谢，非常感谢
- Phenomenal, man. Just brilliant. - Thank you. Thanks.
- 太棒了 - 非常感谢
- Brilliant. - Thanks so much.
- 卡尔文 - 你好
- Calvin.- Hi.
你还记得查理去妓院的那一章吗？
You know that chapter where Charlie goes to the whorehouse?
是不是因为查理母亲的蓝色围裙你才让妓女穿蓝色呢？
Did you dress the whores blue because it's the color of his mother's apron?
抱歉…
I'm sorry...
你是怎么找到投稿的地方的呢？
How did you know where to send your manuscript?
我查了查
I looked it up.
那是当然
Oh, of course.
之前你那么成功现在想起来会不会很奇怪呢？
Is it weird for you that you used to be so successful?
你在这
There's the man.
塞勒斯，你该提醒我这些事
Cyrus, you gotta remind me about these things.
兄弟，你得看看我给你发的短信
You have to check your messages, buddy.
我该穿得正式一些
I would've worn something nicer.
你是天才，没人在意你穿什么
No one cares what you're wearing.You are a genius.
别说我是天才
Don't use that word.
佩罗塔先生，看这边
Mr. Perrotta, over here.
- 卡尔文才华横溢 - 看这边
- Calvin always had talent.- Over here.
但光有才华显然不够
But that, unfortunately, is not enough.
-  兰登，看这边- 我所做的这一切…
- Langdon, right here! - All I did, really...
是给他指引了正确的方向，就像是把接力棒交给他
...was guide him in the right direction and, uh, like, pass the baton.
梅布尔
Mabel.
什么？
What?
我是梅布尔
I'm Mabel.
- 我们认识吗？- 不认识
- Oh, do I know you? - No, no.
你想要我的电话吗？
Do you want my number?
那是本难得的好书，太棒了
It's a one-off, that book.Great.
- 那是独立乐队的首张专辑 - 谢谢
- It's the first album of an indie band. - Thank you.
它有着自然的炙热感情……
It has that sort of unselfconscious verve...
那个…你不会…
...that, um... That you don't, uh...
之后当然会有创作瓶颈，这个…
Then, of course, there's the second album syndrome, which...
这个我们就不说了
We don't talk about that.
人人都爱这本书，但我们想知道你目前的进度
Everyone loves this book, but we wanna hear what you're doing now.
重要的是现在，在写什么书，能说说吗？
What matters is right now.What are you working on? Are you?
他们爱你，然后抛弃你
They love you, then they throw you away.
- 我是说，如果我要创作角色的话 - 实际上，做普通人
- I mean, if I'm gonna include anybody... - It's actually easier...
生活更轻松
...if you've only ever been mediocre.
如果你已经到达了顶峰
If you've been at the top...
- 嗨，抱歉 -嗨
- Hi. Sorry. - Hi.
- 这就能扼杀你了
- It can kill you.
塞林格是正确的，他…
Yeah, Salinger had the right idea. He...
和你一样首部作品很轰动，然后消失了，明白吗？
Write what you can, then, pssh, disappear, you know?
我喝酒了
So I've had a drink.
但没嗑药，我不…
But no coke. I didn't...No coke.
我不嗑药的
I didn't do any coke.
史考特
Scotty?
抱歉这么晚才回来，小家伙
Sorry I'm late, buddy.
史考特
Scotty?
史考特，_(:з”∠)_？
Scotty, what the fuck?
她真可爱
She's so cute.
什么？
What?
你的狗狗，她很可爱
Your dog. She's so cute.
它是只公狗
Oh, he's a boy dog.
它刚像女孩一样尿尿
He just peed like a girl.
我们见过吗？
Have we met before?
没有吧
I don't think so.
你介意我画它吗？
Do you mind if I draw him?
别离太近就行
Uh, but don't get too close.
它有点认生
He's a little scared of people.
- 你是画家吗？- 是
- You're an artist? - Yeah.
- 我可是很棒 - 真的吗？
- I'm super good. - Really?
你的狗狗叫什么？
What's your dog's name?
史考特
Uh, Scotty.
- 你是苏格兰人吗？ - 不是
- Are you Scottish? - No.
叫它这名是因为F·斯考特·菲茨杰拉德
I named him for F. Scott Fitzgerald.
- 谁？ - F·斯考特·菲茨杰拉德
- Who? - F. Scott Fitzgerald.
小说家
The novelist.
《了不起的盖茨》的作者
Great Gatsby.
我不怎么看小说
I don't read a lot of fiction.
你没听说过F·斯考特·菲茨杰拉德吗？
You've never heard of F. Scott Fitzgerald?
为什么？他是名人或重要人物吗？
Why? Is he really famous and important?
他大概是这史上最伟大的小说家之一
Well, he's probably one of the greatest novelists who ever lived.
那不失礼吗？
Isn't that disrespectful?
什么？
What?
给你的狗狗起他的名字，这样有点失礼吧
Naming your dog after him? It's a little disrespectful.
- 不，这只是个象征 - 挑衅的象征
- No, it's a gesture. - Yeah, an aggressive gesture.
想想吧，你是小说家，你觉得那家伙出类拔萃
Think about it. You're a novelist. You think this guy's the greatest.
你用他的名字来命名你的狗来藐视他
So you name your dog after him to cut him down to size.
这样你就能在他脖子上栓根绳子…
This way,you can put him on a leash...
然后大喊“坏小子史考特”…
...and yell "Bad Scotty"...
觉得在室内小便觉得高人一等
...and feel all superior because you pee inside.
尽管藐视你的偶像，伙计，我支持你
Kill your idols, man.I'm all for it.
走了，史考特
All right. Scotty.
等等
Hang on.
-  真漂亮 - 对啊
- This is beautiful. - Yeah.
虽然你的狗狗像女孩一样尿尿，但我还是喜欢它
Your dog might pee like a lady, but I like him anyway.
你说什么？
Hey, what did you just say?
我就喜欢它这样
I like him just the way he is.
对了
Yes.
就是这样
Yes. Yes.
“映入眼帘，好似回流之血”
"...pooled into his eyes as though... Rushed back like blood...
“卡尔文脸红了”
Calvin flushed with..."
你是个天才
You're a genius.
我以为我们不会用“天才”这词儿
I thought we weren't gonna use that word.
你真是聪明绝顶，“再不好我都喜欢”
You are really, really super fucking smart."I'd like it to be bad."
我很高兴你找到了能激发灵感的素材
I'm glad you found something that inspires you.
只是激发灵感吗？
Inspires me?
我文思泉涌，废寝忘食
It overwhelms me.I literally cannot sleep or eat.
我只想写作
All I want I do is write.
今天我差点就不想来了，因为我想和她在一起
I mean, I almost didn't come here today because I didn't wanna be away from her.
-  天哪 - 怎么了？
- Oh, God.- What?
我的天，我说不出口
Oh, my God.Oh, I can't say it out loud.
- 这事儿太离谱了 - 我就喜欢听你说离谱的事儿
- It's too stupid. - I love it when you say stupid things.
- 不，这次真是离谱到家了 - 好吧
- Oh, no, this is really profoundly stupid. - Okay.
我写的男主角…
Okay, so the guy I'm writing...
恩，他叫什么？
Yeah, what's his name?
卡尔文
Uh, Calvin.
我得改改，我以自己为蓝本创造了他
I'm gonna change it. Uh, anyway, there's a lot of me in him.
我想说的是…
What I'm trying to say is...
我之所以写东西是因为我想和她在一起
...it's almost like I'm writing to spend time with her.
- 谁？- 女主角
- Who? - The girl.
小说女主角，这…我晚上去睡觉…
The one I'm writing. It's...I go to sleep at night...
只是为了用打字机继续创造她
...just waiting to get to my typewriter so I can be with her.
就像是…就像是我爱上了她
It's like...It's like I'm falling in love with her.
- 太好了 - 我不能爱上一个我虚构出来的角色
- That's wonderful. - I can't fall in love with a girl I write.
- 为什么不能呢？ - 因为她不存在
- Why not? - Because she's not real.
- 真的吗？你确定吗？ - 我确定她不存在
- Isn't she? Are you sure? - No. Yes.
她只是我虚构出来的人物
She's some motherfucking product of my imagination!
- 莱拉对我特别不好 - 我知道
- Oh, Lila treated me so badly. - I know.
谁会在对方父亲过世时提分手？
Who leaves someone after their father dies?
不能好好爱你的人
Someone who couldn't love you properly.
- 无情荡妇 - 够了
- Someone who is a heartless slut. - Okay.
- 跟我谈谈她 - 我不想再提莱拉了
- Well, tell me about her. - I don't wanna talk about Lila anymore.
我指的是小说女主角，跟我聊聊她
Well, I meant this girl that you're writing.Tell me about her.
她叫露比
Ruby.
露比·斯帕克斯
Ruby Sparks.
今年26岁，在俄亥俄州代顿市长大
Twenty-six years old. Raised in Dayton, Ohio.
- 为什么是代顿？ - 听来很浪漫
- Why Dayton? - Sounds romantic.
露比的初次心动对象是亨弗莱·鲍嘉和约翰·列侬
Ruby's first crushes were Humphrey Bogart and John Lennon.
当发现他们其实已经过世时她哭了一天
Cried the day she found out they were already dead.
高中时露比因为和美术老师上床而被开除了
Ruby got kicked out of high school for sleeping with her art teacher...
西班牙老师也行，我还没想好
...or maybe her Spanish teacher. I haven't decided yet.
露比不会开车，也没电脑
Ruby can't drive. She doesn't own a computer.
她讨厌她的中间名，蒂凡尼
She hates her middle name, which is Tiffany.
她一直支持弱者
She always, always roots for the underdog.
她很复杂，这也是我最喜欢的地方
She's complicated.That's what I like best about her.
有时候露比会很粗心
Ruby's not so good at life sometimes.
她忘记查看账单或兑现发票…
She forgets to open bills or cash checks and...
她的前男友49岁
Her last boyfriend was 49.
前前男友是个酒鬼
The one before that was an alcoholic.
她预感到生活即将发生变化并且很期待
She can feel a change coming. She's looking for it.
期待什么？
Looking for what?
新鲜的事物
Something new.
- 感觉很好吧？ - 歇会儿行吗？
- Feels good, right? - Can we stop a second?
为什么？你还好吧
Why? You all right?
- 苏 - 干嘛？
- Hey, Sue. - Yeah?
没买着辣椒粉，我买了孜然
They didn't have paprika,so I got cumin.
- 安静点，别出声 - 它们没啥区别吧
- Shh, shh! - They're the same thing, right?
麦尔斯刚睡着，你要把他吵醒了，我就揍你
Miles went down.If you wake him, I will beat you.
卡尔文，你得谢谢我帮你清理烤箱
Calvin? You need to thank me because I cleaned your oven.
- 苏西，谢啦 - 我的女人
- Thank you, Susie. - Oh, my woman.
够了，你满身臭汗，把你的手拿开
Okay. You're sweaty.Get your mitts off of me.
-  苏西，你是不是刮…？ - 你都没告诉我你跟别人睡过了啊
- Susie, did you happen to sha...? - You didn't tell me you were getting laid.
- 哈利 - 我只是说说
- Harry. - I'm just saying.
他说自己忙于创作没时间去我们家
He claims to be writing too much to haul his ass to our house.
事实是他只是性趣盎然
But turns out, he's just getting too much poon.
- 哈利，我发誓… - 我没和谁上床
- Harry, I swear to God... - I'm not getting any poon.
是吗？
Oh, yeah?
你跟我说说这谁的啊
Whose is that?You tell me.
我的神，史考特
Oh, my God. Scotty.
- 是史考特的吗？ - 不，史考特…
- It's Scotty's? - No. Scotty...
别让孩子碰那玩意儿，麦尔斯，别…
Don't let the baby touch that. Miles, don't...
- 苏西，孩子喜欢着呢 - 不，他不喜欢
- Suse, he likes it. - No, he doesn't like it.
- 史考特一直往家拖这些东西 - 看样子他喜欢啊
- Scotty's been dragging them in. - He seems to love it.
它一直倒腾隔壁怪邻居的垃圾桶
He goes through my weird neighbor's garbage.
- 这是别人不要了的胸衣吗？ - 是脏的
- So that's a random dirty bra? - It's dirty.
真恶心，孩子都开始咳嗽了
That's gross.You made him cough.
卡尔文，别收了，扔掉
Calvin, don't put it away. Throw it away.
我发誓，要是你妈知道…
I swear, if your mother knew...
- 卡尔文，这都是什么啊 - 什么？
- Calvin, what is this? - What's what?
-  没什么 - 哈利，过来
- Nothing. - Harry, get over here.
别翻了
Uh, please, don't.
- 这些是内裤吗？ - 娘的
- Are these panties? - Fuck off.
我发誓史考特一直往家里拖这些东西
I swear, Scotty's been dragging them in.
- 对，史考特是罪魁祸首 - 闭嘴
- Right. Scotty. - Shut up.
卡尔文，把这些扔了
Calvin, throw these away.
- 苏西，我去看看哈利 - 好
- Hey, Susie, I'm gonna check on Harry. - Okay.
- 告诉他一会儿得走了 - 好
- Tell him we have to go soon. - Okay.
怎么样？
So?
你打算怎么写？
Where do you see this going?
不清楚，这才刚开头
Well, I don't know. I just started.
这是个爱情故事吧
This is a love story, right?
现在谁会看爱情故事呢？
Who reads love stories?
女人
Women.
我告诉你，女人不会看这个
And I'm telling you,no woman's gonna wanna read this.
为什么？故事很浪漫啊
Why not? It's romantic.
因为性情古怪，生活一团糟还可爱的女人并不存在
Quirky, messy women whose problems only make them endearing are not real.
完了
Period.
怎么说来着，得“写你所经历过的”
What do they say,"write what you've been through"?
- 写你了解的东西 - 对，写你了解的东西
- Write what you know. - Exactly. Write what you know.
- 我认识露比这样的女孩儿 - 是吗？
- I've known girls like Ruby. - Yeah?
谁啊
Who?
女孩儿
Girls.
- 莱拉吗？ - 不是该死的莱拉
- Lila? - Not fucking Lila.
- 你就谈过一次恋爱 - 谈了5年
- You've had one relationship. - For five years.
你俩都没同居过
You never even lived together.
听我说，卡尔文，蜜月顶个屁用
I'm telling you, Calvin, the honeymoon shit, it doesn't last.
- 我知道 - 和女人生活在一起就不一样了
- I know that. - Women are different up close.
我爱苏西…
I love Susie...
但她是怪人
...but she's a weirdo.
有时候，她没缘由地刻薄
Sometimes, she's mean as fuck for no reason.
她是一个真实的人
She's a person.
你写得不是真人，明白吗？
You haven't written a person, okay?
- 你写的是女孩儿 - 够了，管他呢
- You've written a girl. - All right, whatever.
作家不会给人看还在创造阶段的书稿
Writers don't show their work to people at this stage.
我也许不会继续写下去
I might not even finish it.
因为…我不喜欢这么跟人说
Because...And don't, like, tell people about it.
听着，我没说你不能写下去
Listen. I'm not saying you can't write.
我是说…
I'm saying...
你一点儿都不了解女人
...you don't know jack shit about women.
瘦杆儿，剩菜剩饭别浪费了
Don't let those leftovers go to waste,okay, skinny?
明天去健身房吗？
Gym tomorrow?
我要见塞德斯
Uh, I'm seeing Cyrus.
- 星期五？ - 就星期五
- Maybe Friday? - Friday.
- 我知道 - 小子，还好吧
- I know. - You okay, bud?
没事儿
Yes.
这东西滴得到处都是
This thing is dripping everywhere.
你到底打算怎么吃啊？
How are you supposed to eat this thing?
怎么了？
What?
你真不是我菜
You're so not my type.
为什么说我不是你的菜？
What do you mean I'm not your type?
通常我会找更专断的男人
I usually go for guys who are a little more, um, assertive.
- 我就那样 - 不
- I'm assertive. - Ha, ha. No.
你是固执，这不一样
You're stubborn. That's different.
我的某个男朋友
I had this one boyfriend...
说我没意思
...who told me I wasn't funny...
但其实我幽默感挺好的
...but that I have a good sense of humor...
他讲笑话我都笑
...because I laughed at his jokes.
为什么你会和那种类型的男人约会？
Why would you date a guy like that?
年少无知，你肯定也有后悔的事
I was young.You must have things you regret.
不一定
Not really.
目前一直都进展顺利
Everything's been perfect so far.
所以你和他们约会是因为
So that's what you're looking for in a guy?
他们够二吗？
Douchiness?
不知道
I don't know.
我想我一直在找你
I guess I was looking for you.
花了我不少时间才终于找到你
It just took me a while to find you.
- 露比 - 跳啊
- Ruby. - Jump!
初次见我时你是什么感觉呢？
What did you think the first time you saw me?
我认为你是我见过最美的女孩
I thought you were the most beautiful girl I ever saw.
了解我之后你失望吗？
Were you disappointed when you got to know me?
你怎么能这么问呢？
How can you ask that?
我的生活一团糟
I'm such a mess.
我爱你的不羁
I love your mess.
初次见你时，我想
The first time I saw you, I thought:
快看那个男孩
"Look at that boy.
我会生生世世都爱他
I'm going to love him forever and ever and ever."
- 若你厌倦我了怎么办？ - 不会
- What if you get sick of me? - I won't.
我保证
I promise.
喂，该死
Hello. Shit.
该死
Shit.
喂，见鬼了
Hello. Damn it.
好了，不是
Okay. No.
- 喂 - 塞德斯
- Hello. - Cyrus.
- 你究竟跑哪去了 - 抱歉
- Where the fuck are you? - Uh, sorry.
我写了一晚上，睡死了，我马上到
I was writing, I fell asleep. I'll be right there.
要是你还没准备好谈新小说，没事的
Look, if you aren't ready to talk about this, it's fine.
不，我想给你看看我的成果
No... No, no. I wanna show you what I have.
我觉得你会特激动的
I think you're gonna be really excited.
我当然会激动，这样吧，我去把午餐推迟了
Of course, I'll be excited. Okay, uh,here's what I'll do. I'll push my lunch.
没问题，现在出发的话，15分钟后到
Okay. All right. Well, uh, if I leave now,I should be there in 15 minutes.
- 好 - 前提是不堵车
- All right. - If there isn't any traffic.
该死，史考特
Oh, damn it. Scotty.
- 什么？ - 没事儿，我的狗要尿尿
- What? - Uh, nothing. Uh, my dog has to pee.
- 我把它领到后院去 - 我带它出去吧
- I'll, uh, put him in the backyard. - I'll take him out.
- 太好了，谢谢 - 卡尔？
- Great. Thank you. - Cal?
卡尔？
Cal?
喂
Hello?
昨晚我很想你
I missed you in bed last night.
- 有好思路了吗？ - 你还在吗？
- Did you get some good writing done? - Are you there?
- 我的神 - 想吃点东西吗？
- Oh, God. - Hey, you want a bite?
- 早餐麦片吃吗？ - 他应该是没信号了
- It's Crispix. - I think I lost him.
神呐，成真了，这次成真了
God, it's happening.It's really happening this time.
- 他们会把我关进医院 - 出什么事儿了？
- They're gonna hospitalize me. - What's wrong?
大家都以为我聪明绝顶，其实我是精神病
They all thought I was so smart,but it turns out I was just batshit.
- 卡尔文？ - 我的妈呀
- Calvin? - What the fuck?
卡尔文
Calvin.
这不是真的，这不是真的
It's not real. It's not real.
这不是真的
It's not real.
我正在做梦
Okay, you're dreaming.
我在做梦
You're dreaming.
在做梦
You're dreaming...
现在得醒来
...and you're going to wake up...
就是现在
...right now.
该死
Oh, shit.
- 卡尔文，你在生我气吗？ - 天呐
- Calvin? Are you mad at me? - Oh.
我的神呐，这不是真的
Oh, God. It's not real.
这不是真的，这不是真的，这不是真的
It's not real. It's not real. It's not real.
医生
Doctor...
喂，罗森塔尔大夫，我是卡尔文·威尔菲尔兹 我出了点状况
Hi, Dr. Rosenthal. It's Calvin Weir-Fields.Something has come up...
若你能尽快打来我感激不尽，谢谢
...and I'd appreciate it if you called me as soon as possible. Thank you.
- 露比 - 干嘛
- Ruby? - Hey.
我觉得你也许饿了，就做了些鸡蛋
I thought you might be hungry,so I'm making you some eggs.
- 怎么了？ - 没事儿
- What's wrong? - Oh, nothing.
没事儿
Nothing, uh...
这些东西是你的吗？
Are these, by any chance, yours?
当然是我的
Yeah, of course, they are.
不然还能是谁的呢？
Who else would they belong to?
上帝啊
Oh, my God.
- 你和其他人约会了吗？ - 没有
- Are you seeing someone else? - Oh, no.
不，不，我没有
No, no, no, I'm not...
除了你我谁也没见
I'm not seeing anyone other than you.
我能先离开一会儿吗？
Will you excuse me?
还记得老爸以前说我异想天开吗？
Remember how Dad used to say I had an overactive imagination?
你是说露比现在在你屋里？
Are you saying Ruby is in your house?
我从今早开始见到她
I started seeing her this morning.
就像是电影-迷离世界（1950），不同的是她不是大兔子
It's like that movie Harvey, except she's not a giant rabbit.
看上去她不知道自己是想象出来的
It's not like she knows she's imaginary, either.
她认为我们正和书中描写的一样在恋爱
She thinks we're in the relationship in my book.
吓死我了
It is freaking me out.
- 我正在开会 - 但这是紧急情况
- I'm in the middle of a meeting. - But this is an emergency.
我搞不好已经疯了
I may be losing my mind.
- 请稍等 - 哈利，哈利
- Just give me one sec. Just... - Harry. Harry.
露比根本不可能出现在你家
There's no possible way that Ruby's in your house...
因为她是你虚构的角色
...because she's not a real person.
我知道客观上她是虚构的，但我跟你说…
I know objectively she is not real, but I'm telling you...
我看得见她，闻得到她的味道
...I can see her, I can smell her.
她触碰我的时候我有感觉
When she touched me, I could feel it.
她正在我厨房里做鸡蛋，真鸡蛋
She's making eggs in my kitchen. Actual eggs.
真不错
That's great.
卡尔文，我上班呢，正在开一个非常重要的会议
Calvin, I am at work.I'm in the middle of a very important meeting.
现在管不了你那档子烂事儿
I cannot deal with your shit right now.
听我说，离开家去外面…
Listen to me.I want you to leave the house...
见见朋友，一个看不见露比的朋友
...see a friend. A friend who can't see your imaginary friend.
如果到了晚上还是如此，我们再谈，行吗？
If this is still an issue tonight, we'll talk, okay?
好，我去给朋友打电话
Okay. I'll phone a friend.
抱歉，我是…
Sorry about that, I was...
科比周末打算开个烧烤派对。你们周末有约了吗？
Kobe's having a barbecue this weekend. You got plans this weekend?
我是卡尔文
It's Calvin.
威尔菲尔兹，你的高中同学
Weir-Fields. From high school.
是，那个作家
Yeah, the writer.
西班牙语课上我坐你旁边
I sat next to you in Spanish class.
其实，我得挂了
Uh, actually, I gotta go.
你要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
- 外面 - 哪儿？
- Out. - Where?
商店
To the store.
干什么？
What for?
买些东西
To get some stuff.
- 我能去吗？ - 不能
- Can I come? - No.
- 为什么不行？ - 因为…
- Why not? - Because.
- 拜托 - 不能
- Please? - No.
拜托
Please?
南加州和洛杉矶电台（隶属NPR）
- Point-nine KCRW.
接下来将为KCRW会员派发门票
Up next, tickets for KCRW members.
如果您在过去的90天内未赢得任何奖励…
If you haven't won anything from us in the last 90 days...
听说公墓那边有个僵尸电影节
I hear they're doing a zombie film festival at the cemetery.
你想去吗？每人被咬一口我们就喝一杯
You wanna go? We could do a shot every time someone gets bitten.
好，再见
Okay. Bye.
再见？你要去哪儿？
Bye? Where are you going?
哪儿也不去
Nowhere.
费加罗咖啡店，我去见个朋友，用不了多久
Cafe Figaro. I've got this friend. It won't take long.
我该干些什么呢？
What am I supposed to do?
呆这儿，逛逛街
Stay here. Enjoy the shops.
我马上就回来
I'll be back soon.
当我没有马上接到你的电话
When I didn't hear from you right away...
我还以为你把我的号码弄丢了
...I figured you had lost my number or something.
至少我室友这么认为
At least that's what my roommate said must have happened.
不，你的号码我留着，实际上，我遇见你的那晚
Oh, no, I didn't lose your number.Uh, actually the, uh, night I met you...
我开始写作了，那花了我不少时间
...I started writing something,so that's been really consuming.
你遇见我的那晚吗？
The night you met me?
我是不是？
Am I?
没什么，没什么
Never mind. Ha, ha. Never mind.
你是不是写我了？
Um, am I in it?
- 现在不能说 - 当然
- I can't really talk about it. - Right, of course.
如果你写了我，小说出版发售的时候
But if I am, like, when it comes out  in stores and stuff...
- 你会跟我说那个角色是我吗？ - 我没写你
...will you tell me which character I am? You're not in it.
我知道，但如果写了呢？
Right, but if I am?
我会告诉你
I will let you know.
太好了
Okay. Awesome. Awesome.
你经常这么干吗?
So, um, do you do this a lot?
- 干什么？ - 午间约炮
- Do what? - Meet up in the middle of the day for sex.
不，不，我只想找人说会儿话
No. No, that's not... I just wanted someone to talk to.
这样啊
Right. Right.
男人永远不会只想和女人说说话
Well, men never just wanna talk to women.
- 我就是这样 - 如果你坚持的话
- I do. - If you say so.
你成年了吗？
Uh, heh, are you even legal?
还没到合法饮酒的年纪，但
I mean, not to drink, but, yeah.
当然，你想…
Of course. Do you, um...?
你想去别的地方吗？
Do you wanna go someplace?
- 嗨 - 抱歉，什么？
- Hi. - Sorry, what?
你想去我那儿吗？
Do you wanna go to my place?
- 嗨 - 抱歉
- Hi. - Sorry.
- 抱歉 - 出什么事了？
- I'm sorry. - What's going on?
- 打扰二位了吗？ - 我幻听了
- Am I interrupting? - I thought I heard something.
- 你想去其他地方吗？ - 卡尔文
- Do you wanna get out of here? - Calvin.
- 你认识这个女生吗？ - 当然，你好，我是露比，卡尔文的女朋友
- Do you know this girl? - Yeah. Hi, I'm Ruby, Calvin's girlfriend.
我想我没见过你
I don't think we've met.
没见过
Uh, no.
我是梅布尔，我走了
Um, I'm Mabel. I was just going.
- 你能看见她吗？ - 当然，她看得见我
- You can see her? - Yeah, she can see me.
我也看得见她
I can see her.
- 你能看见她 - 我们别把事情闹大了
- You can see her. - Let's not make this worse, all right?
- 抱歉，我不知情 - 是哈利让你故意来试探我的吗？
- Sorry, I didn't know. - Did Harry put you up to this?
- 什么，这事儿你哥也有份？ - 什么？
- What, your brother is in on this? - What?
露比，很高兴见到你，卡尔文，祝你写作顺利
Ruby, it was very nice meeting you. Calvin, have fun writing.
那女的他妈是谁？
Who the fuck was that?
- 你能看见她吗？ - 卡尔文，那女的是谁？
- Can you see her? - Calvin, who was that?
- 我能看见她吗？ - 他能看见我吗？你在干…？住手
- Can I see her? - Can he see me? What are you...? Stop.
伙计，你有毛病啊？
What's wrong with you, man?
她是个活人
She's real.
别，露比
Oh, no. Ruby!
露比！露比！
Ruby! Ruby.
- 离我远点儿 - 露比，露比
- Get away from me! - Ruby! Ruby!
- 滚开，滚开 - 露比
- Get away! Get away! - Ruby!
-  露比，别这样，听我说 - 放开
- Ruby, please, listen to me. - Let go!
- 住手 - 听我说，露比，冷静
- Stop! - Listen to me. Calm down. Ruby.
- 离我远点儿 - 你还好吧？
- Get away from me! - Hey, you okay?
需要我叫警察吗？
You want me to call the police?
不用，谢谢，他是个完全的混蛋
No. Thank you. He's just being a complete asshole.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
确定
Yeah.
谢谢，我没事
Thank you, I'm fine.
- 露比 - 你滚开
- Ruby. - You stay away.
我早就该知道，你一直表现得很奇怪，住手
God, I should have known. You've been acting like such a freak... Stop!
放开我
Let go of me!
放我下来
Put me down!
放我下来，不然我开始叫了
Put me down or I'm gonna scream!
- 露比 - 住手
- Ruby. - Stop it!
- 放我下来 - 露比
- Put me down! - Ruby?
上帝，停下来
Oh, my God, stop! Ow!
停下，别咬了，别咬了
Shh! Stop it. Oh, do not bite. Do not bite.
听我说
Listen to me. Shh, shh.
事情发展太快，我解释不清楚
There is a lot that is new here, more than I can tell you.
我无法接受这一切，你懂吗？
I'm having trouble processing it all, okay?
那就和我谈谈啊
Then talk to me about it.
别和其他女孩约会
Don't go on a date with another girl.
我不是在约会
I wasn't on a date.
- 你究竟是怎么了？ - 我不知道，对不起
- What is going on with you? - I don't know. I'm sorry.
我只是思维混乱
Oh, I'm just having trouble...
无法正常处理眼前的情况
...wrapping my head around the reality of this situation.
你就在这里
That you're here.
你是真的
That you're real.
这一切太不可思议了
It all seems pretty incredible.
什么？
What?
傻瓜，吻我啊
Kiss me, stupid.
天啊
Holy shit.
我把内裤脱了
I took off my panties
什么？
What?
我没穿内裤
I am not wearing any panties!
听不见
What?
我知道难以置信，但你得相信我
Look, I know it's a lot to take in, but you have to believe me.
她是个活人
She's real.
我不知道这是怎么回事
I don't know how or why...
但是她就那么出现了，是真实的
...but she's here and she's real.
我喜欢这种感觉
And I like it.
-“真实”是指别人也能看见 - 我一直在跟你说这个
- "Real" as in other people can see her. - That's what I'm trying to tell you.
我们一起去餐厅，带史考特去公园遛弯儿
We've been to restaurants. We take Scotty for walks in the park.
- 大家和她交谈，她很友善 - 不可能
People talk to her. She's very friendly. That's impossible.
显然有可能
It's apparently not.
罗森塔尔大夫怎么说？
What does Dr. Rosenthal say?
你他妈的认真的吗？
Are you fucking serious?
出现幻觉了人们会去看心理医生
People have shrinks for when they start seeing things.
我没出现幻觉
I'm not seeing things.
- 卡尔文，打给他 - 我不打
- Calvin, call him. - I can't.
如果我跟他说露比是我虚构的角色，他不会相信
I told him when she was a character. He won't understand.
- 打给他，不然我告诉老妈 - 他当我是疯子
- Call him or I'm telling Mom. - He'll think I'm crazy.
搞不好你真疯了
You might be crazy.
状况失控了
The situation is crazy.
我没疯
I am not.
听听…？你好
Do you hear...? Hi.
听听你自己说的是什么？你真知道自己在说什么吗？
Do you hear yourself? Do you?Do you hear yourself? Really?
跟一个你虚构的女孩同床共枕绝对不可能
There's no way that you're sleeping with a girl that you made up.
她不知道自己是我创造出来的角色
Hey, so, uh, she doesn't know that I wrote her...
所以底稿的事情一个字儿也不要说
...so don't say anything about the manuscript, okay?
好啦，知道了
Yeah, okay.
露比，你好，见到你真高兴。现在能打给医生了吗？
Hi, Ruby. Great to meet you.Can we call the doctor now?
- 哈利 - 卡尔文
- Harry. - Calvin!
怎么去了那么久？
What took you so long?
- 露比，这是我哥哈利 - 你好
- Hey, Ruby, this is my brother, Harry. - Hey.
- 你好，哈利 - 你好
- Harry. Hi. - Hi.
见到你真高兴
Hi. It's great to meet you.
卡尔文经常说起你
I've heard so much about you from Calvin.
你是露比
You're Ruby.
你是哈利
You're Harry.
来自俄亥俄代顿的画家
The painter from Dayton, Ohio.
- 对 - 是啊
- Yep. - Yep.
留下来吃晚饭吗？我在做肉糜糕
Are you staying for supper? I'm making meat loaf.
她厨艺一流
She's an amazing cook.
我们能否去外面聊聊？
Yeah. Can I talk to you a second? Outside?
好啊
Okay.
你做什么了？从克雷格信息网雇了个演员吗？这不好玩
What did you do? Hire some actress? Craigslist? This isn't funny.
我告诉过你，她就这样出现了
I told you, she just appeared.
- 你是个作家，不是魔术师 - 我知道
You're a writer, not Ricky Jay. I know that.
- 肯定得有合乎逻辑的解释 - 爱是感性的
- There's gotta be some logical explanation. - Love isn't logical.
不，但你知道吗？ 物理学或者玄学也许能解释
No, but you know what is? Physics. Or metaphysics.
- 不会有人凭空出现 - 她出现了
-People don't appear out of thin air. - She did.
- 怎么出现的？ - 我不知道
- How?  - I don't know how.
这是爱，是奇迹
It's love. It's magic.
- 好吧 - 你干什么？
- Okay. - What are you doing?
- 打给你的医生 - 别
- Calling your doctor.  - Don't.
-  哈利，哈利 - 手机给我
- Harry. Harry.  - Give me that.
- 也许我们…手机给我 - 哈利，听我说
- We might... Give me the phone. - Harry, listen to me, please.
还记得你第一次遇见苏西时对我说了什么吗？
Remember what you told me when you met Susie?
- 我肯定没假装她是我创造的- 你说她是你的梦中情人
- I certainly didn't pretend I invented her. - You said that she was your dream girl.
露比是我的梦中情人
That's what happened to me.
哈利，别笑话我
Harry, don't laugh at me.
你就没想过她可能是个骗子吗？
Has it occurred to you that she might be an imposter?
有些妞想接近你，设法看到了你的底稿
Some girl wanted to get close to you, somehow got her hands on what you wrote.
就你看过我的底稿
You're the only one who's read my manuscript.
- 除非你是在开玩笑 - 好了，好了
- So unless you're playing some joke... - Okay, okay, okay.
假设是你创造了她，对她的描述都成真了
Let's say you created this person. Everything you wrote about her came true.
- 即使是细节？ - 是
- Even the smallest things? - Yes.
- 那你有没有再多写点东西？ - 没有
- Have you tried writing more? - No.
写写她
Write something about her.
为什么？她很完美了
Why? She's perfect.
写写她，看看是不是都能成真
Write something about her, see if it comes true.
如果是真的，那我相信你，这是个扯淡的奇迹
If it does, then you're right and this is a fucking miracle.
但如果没有…
And if nothing happens...
我们就得去警局
...maybe we go to the police.
- 别打给… - 进屋去，表现得正常点儿，上去吧
- Don't call... - Just go in there and act normal. Go up.
- 你表现得正常点儿 - 我又不会说…
- You act normal. - I'm not gonna say...
我们得上楼检查些东西，上网
We're gonna go upstairs and check on something, uh, online.
你俩在外面嗑药了吗？
Were you guys getting stoned out there?
这就是我停笔的地方
Okay, here's where I left off.
写些我们马上能察觉的东西
It has to be something we notice right away, okay?
显而易见的事情
Something obvious.
- 她的穿着吗？ - 好，对
- What she's wearing? - Yes. Yes.
她的穿着
What she's wearing.
她穿着什么？
What was she wearing?
是粉色吗？
Was it pink?
我知道了
I got it.
好，好
Okay. Okay.
写她能说流利的法语
Write that she speaks fluent French.
好了，写就行
Yeah, just put it down.
我来写
I'll do it. I...
露比说着一口流利的法语，但她却没意识到（= =，法语无能）
- 我马上就回来，我得做些修改 - 别，等等，别走
- I'll be right back. I have to do something. - No, wait, hold it.
卡尔文
Calvin.
红酒来了
Bottle of vino.
太好了，你哥看起来需要喝一杯
Great. Your brother looks like he could use a drink.
我得说这是我吃过最棒的肉糜糕了
I have to say,that's the best meat loaf I've ever had.
谢谢
Thank you.
家传菜谱
It's a family recipe.
我不能居功
I can't really take credit.
这么说你的…你家在俄亥俄吗？
So your... Your family's in Ohio?
对，我还是个婴儿的时候父母就在一场事故中过世了
Yeah. Actually, my parents died when I was a baby in an accident...
所以我居无定所
...and I got moved around a lot.
我想暂时不会换居所了
I guess the habit stuck.
- 六年内我辗转过九个城市，所以… - 九个吗？
- I've lived in nine cities in six years, so... -  Nine?
- 是啊 - 那可真够多的
- Yeah. - Wow, that's a lot of cities.
抱歉，我一直喋喋不休
I'm so sorry. I'm totally monopolizing this conversation.
没有，你的经历很奇妙
No. This is fascinating.
请继续
Please, keep going. Please.
你们俩兄弟人真好
What nice boys.
你妈妈肯定很自豪，男孩这么得体很难得
Your mom must be so proud. It's hard to raise a decent guy.
我在想某人得有多大能耐才能…
Oh, I think a person would have to do something pretty amazing...
塑造出一个好女人
...to produce a good woman.
好了，就到这吧
Okay. Great.
你们很投机，但哈利得走了
Uh, you guys like each other. I think Harry has to go now.
对吧，哥？
Right, buddy?
他有时候就是个控制狂，对吧？
He can be such a control freak, right?
- 我马上回来 - 晚安
- I'll be right back. - Good night.
- 下次见 - 怎么看？
- See you soon, I hope. - Hey. So?
- 上车 - 什么？
- Get in the car. - What?
- 上车 - 为什么？你要干吗？
- Get in the car. - Why? What?
太疯狂了！
That was insane!
- 哈利… - 太疯狂了
- Harry... - This is insane.
你用想象力造出了一个女人
You manifested a woman with your mind.
- 老妈知道了会被吓坏的 - 你不能跟妈说
- Mom's gonna fucking freak. - Whoa, you can't tell Mom.
- 为什么不？她就喜欢新鲜事物 - 说真的
- Why not? She loves all this New Age shit. - Seriously...
你谁都不能说，老妈和苏西也不行
...you can't tell anybody. Not Mom, not Susie. No one.
- 这太奇妙了，为什不能说呢？ - 大家会当她是个怪胎
- This is amazing. How can I not tell? - They'll think she's a freak.
- 我们要假装她是你女朋友吗？ - 她就是我女朋友
- We're gonna pretend she's your girlfriend? - She is my girlfriend.
来真的？
Seriously?
- 为什么不行呢？ - 你的女朋友
- Why not? - Your girlfriend.
- 怪事总会发生 - 我不这么想
- Stranger things have happened. - I don't think so.
我觉得这是史上最奇怪的事了
I think this is pretty much the strangest thing that's ever happened, ever.
你打算和她结婚？生小孩？
You gonna marry her? Have kids with her?
-我不知道 - 但那不和乱伦差不多了吗？
- I don't know. - But wouldn't that be like incest?
- 或者说是意念乱伦？ - 我不在乎
- Or mind-cest? - I don't care.
我爱她
I love her.
请别搞砸了
Please don't ruin this for me.
保证你不会告诉任何人
Promise me, no one.
好吧
Fine.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那么你能改造她咯
Oh, hey, so you can,like, change her.
我想可以吧
I guess.
某些特殊的嗜好也能得到满足咯
You could, like, tweak things if you wanted.
特殊的嗜好吗？你指什么？
Tweak? What do you mean?
我不知道，比如大胸长腿之类
I don't know, like anything.Big tits, long legs...
- 我喜欢她的小细腿 - 很多次我都想在苏西身上装个按钮
- I like her little legs. - Know how many times I wanted a button...
摁完她就不做那些烦人的事了
...to make Susie stop doing all the annoying shit she does?
我是说，只要你想，随时都可以口交
I mean, you could get blow jobs whenever you wanted.
露比本来就喜欢口交
Ruby loves giving blow jobs.
那是现在，几天几月后呢？
Now, but what about in a couple months or days?
女人让男人琢磨不透，现在我看着苏西还会问自己
Women are mysterious creatures.I still look at Susie like:
你是谁？你是谁？
"Who are you? Who are you?"
我了解露比，哈利，我给了她生命
I know Ruby, Harry. I wrote her.
所以你能支配她的行为
So you can make her,like, do anything.
为了全世界的男同胞们
For men everywhere...
答应我千万要好好利用这福利
...tell me you're not gonna let that go to waste.
我不会再提笔写她了
I will never write about her again.
卡尔文
Calvin?
他还喜欢我吧
So did he like me?
他爱你
He loved you.
别，别打扰我
Stop, stop, stop.
如果是我妈打来的，请别…
Hey, if it's my mom, please don't...
喂
Hello?
喂，有人在吗？我没…
Hello, is anyone there? I don't...
老妈好
Hi, Mom.
甜心，刚才不确定你在呢
Oh, hi, sweetie. Hi.I wasn't sure you were there.
老妈你想干什么？
What do you want, Mom?
我想知道这周末你能来看我吗？
I was wondering if you're gonna make it up this weekend.
跟你说了这周末不行，我们忙的很
I told you we can't this weekend. We're busy.
忙什么呢？
Oh, with what?Busy with what?
你哥说你老早就没写东西了
Your brother says you haven't been writing.
- 他不知道具体情况 - 你和这个女孩儿都腻了几个月了
- He doesn't know. - You've been with this girl for months.
我都还没见过她呢，我都开始觉得她根本不存在了
I haven't even met her.I'm beginning to think she doesn't exist.
什么？存在，她当然存在
What? No. I mean, yes.
- 那什么时候能见她呢？ - 快了
- So when can I meet her? - Soon.
下周好吗？哈利和苏西也会来
Next weekend?Harry and Susie will be here.
拜托，我们去吧
Come on, please?
妈，我们有打算了
Look, we have plans.
我一会儿打给你，正开着车呢
I'm gonna call you later, okay?I'm driving.
为什么我们不能去大索尔？ （全美50大景点之一，隶属南加州）
Why can't we go to Big Sur?
我们得找个人照顾史考特
Uh, well, we'd have to find someone to watch Scotty.
我们可以带它一起去
We could take him with us.
我不知道，莫特…
I don't know. Mort...
我妈家很怪异
Their house is weird.
你不想我和你妈见面
You don't want me to meet your mom.
我当然想让你见见我妈
Of course,I want you to meet my mom.
我圣诞节请她过来玩行吗？
I'll invite her down for Christmas, okay?
你知道德维尔街有家新开张的咖啡店吗？
Hey, you know that coffee shop on Dwyer? The new one?
知道
Yes.
我在考虑要不要去那里打工
I was thinking maybe I could try to get a job there.
我说过我全力支持你的绘画事业
Well, I told you, I'm happy to support you while you paint.
亲爱的，我有些累了
Honey, I'm sort of tired.
好吧
Okay.
我把灯关了
Let's turn out the light, then.
如果我不在你身边，也许你就能多写些东西了
It's just, maybe if I wasn't around, you could get more writing done.
我俩刚见面的时候你不是在写东西吗？
Weren't you working on something when we first met?
卡尔文？
Calvin?
你在干吗？
What are you doing?
收拾收拾去大索尔
Just packing for Big Sur.
真的吗？
Really?
当然
Yeah.
瞧瞧这地方
Wow, look at this place.
好了，我们到了
All right, this is it.
这可是你要来的
You asked for it.
你完全不用担心
You have nothing to worry about.
要不今晚我们去别处过夜吧
Look, why don't we stay somewhere else tonight?
就我俩，周围旅馆很多
Just you and me. There's a thousand bed-and-breakfasts around.
- 宝贝儿，没事的 - 两人世界会本来很浪漫的
- Honey, it's gonna be great. - It could be romantic.
-  终于来了 - 你好
- Finally. - Hi.
- 你来了 - 你好
- You're here! - Hi.
- 好了 - 史考特，你好
- Okay. - Hi, Scotty.
- 你好，快点，快点，史考特 - 好了
- Hi. Come on. Come on, Scotty. - Okay
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hello. Hi.
- 你好，我是露比 - 你好，露比
- Hi. I'm Ruby. - Hi, Ruby.
这花园真是太漂亮了
Wow, your garden is so amazing.
这里的每一株植物都有药用价值
All the plants have medicinal purposes.
- 药用 - 对
- Medicinal.- Yeah.
太酷了
That is very cool.
- 叹为观止 - 是啊
- This is incredible. - Yeah.
他从1980年开始建造这个花园，一直扩大规模
He started it in 1980 and he just keeps adding to it.
这是他的杰作
It's his masterpiece.
- 莫特建了这个花园吗？ - 对啊
- Mort built all of this? - Yeah.
- 你相信吗？ - 我当然相信
- Can you believe it?  - Yes, I can.
这就是我们生活的地方
And this is where we live.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
美呆了
This is so beautiful.
有种置身于寺庙之中的感觉
I feel like I'm in some kind of temple.
上帝啊，真不敢相信你这么说了
Oh, my God,I can't believe you said that.
- 卡尔文，她的感觉真准 - 怎么了？
- Calvin, she is so intuitive. - What? What? What?
这些木材是莫特从阿米什人社区弄来的，有神之祝福
Mort got this wood from Amish land. It was blessed.
砖块来自一座已被拆毁的旧天主教会学校
And the bricks come from an old Catholic school that was torn down.
难以置信
That's incredible.
楼梯，卧室
Stairway, bedroom.
哈利睡这儿
That's where Harry will sleep.
这是我的书房，别进去
This is my study. Don't go in there.
我还在整理书籍
I'm re-alphabetizing.
你俩就睡这儿了
And this is where you'll be sleeping.
像个小巢
Oh, it's like a little nest.
老妈，我们住这儿吗？这里没安门
Uh, Mom, we're in here? There are no doors.
宝贝儿，没人关心你在干什么
No one's interested in your business, honey.
这是洗漱间
Well, this is the bathroom.
我们都有各自的
We have our own well.
这是莫特的工作室
This is Mort's workshop!
他做漂流木家具
He makes driftwood furniture!
莫特
Mort!
莫特，亲爱的，孩子们来了
Mort, honey, they're here!
欢迎
Welcome!
这才是好孩子，好孩子
That's a good boy, good boy.
- 它真乖 - 露比…
- He is such a good boy. - So, Ruby...
你念过艺术学校吗？
...did you go to art school?
没，我没受过正式的训练
No, I didn't train formally.
一直零零碎碎地自学
I just sort of picked things up here and there.
做得好，继续保持，这样学得更多
That's right. Just do it.You learn more that way, eh?
我是说，瞧瞧卡尔文
I mean, look at Calvin, eh?
对吧，我的乖儿子
Right, hijo mio?
莫特，能别喂史考特吃东西了吗？
Um, Mort, could you not feed Scotty?
- 别担心，它喜欢 - 它会消化不良
- Aw, don't worry. He loves it. - It'll upset his stomach.
狗是真喜欢吃人的食物
Dogs love human food.They do.
- 不，它们不喜欢 - 喜欢
- No, they don't. - They do.
我年轻时也画画
I painted when I was young.
- 真的吗？ - 是啊
- Did you? - Yeah.
卡尔文从没跟我提起过
Calvin never told me.
他俩的父亲不同意我画
Well, their father didn't approve.
因为她画的是情色主题
Because she painted porn.
- 画裸体模特 - 各种体位
- Nudes. - In positions.
跟色情片差不多
It was basically porn.
哈利，我觉得他们很性感
I think they are very sexy, Harry.
莫特一直鼓励我重新开始画
Mort's been encouraging me to take it up again.
夫人，你应该继续，你擅长此道
You should do it, Mama.You're very good at it.
宝贝
Lovey.
- 你无所不能 - 宝贝
- You're good at everything. - Lovey.
妈妈，一切都很棒
Everything is so good, Mama.
- 甜心 - 都很棒
- Oh, sweetie. - So good.
- 好了 - 开始了，开始了
- Okay. - Let's go, let's go.
还剩一分钟，一分钟
One minute left. One minute.
第一个词
First word!
-  小词（比较常见的词汇） - 不，大词（比较正式的词汇）
- A little word. - No, big word.
- “如果”？“它是”？ - “和”？
- Uh, if. It's. - Uh, and.
- “它是” - “这”，“这”
- It's. - Uh, the, the, the.
- 是… - “什么”
- Well, uh... - What.
-“什么” - 什么？
- What. - What?
“什么”
What.
就是这个词
- 莫特，谢啦 - 你是我们队的
- Thank you, Mort. - You're on our team.
- 第二个词 - 我们才是队友
- Second word. - You're on our team.
- “红杉”吗？ - 她们猜不着
- Uh, redwoods. - They're not gonna get it.
- 你和我，不是他们，“我们”吗？ - “我们”
- You and me. Not them. Us. - Us.
- “我们”…… - “我们”
- We, uh... - Us.
女生的…
A girl's, uh...
胸与屁股
The T's and butt, um...
- 小孩子！女孩？ - 神啊
- Babies! Girls? - Oh, boy.
- “女人” - “女人”吗？
- Women! - Women?
- “什么女人” - 莫特
- "What women." - Mort.
“什么女人”
"What women."
-  谁知女人心？ - 谁知女人心
- What Women Want? - What Women Want.
她们赢了
Oh, they won!
- 谁知女人心？谁选的题？ - 过来
- What Women Want? Who picks that? - Come over here.
- 你太棒了 - 是莫特选的吗？
- You're so good. - Mort? He picked it?
我爱你，上帝，你得奖了
I love you. Oh, my God. You win the prize.
- 我是她的教练 - 你这样违反了游戏规则
- I'm her tainer - But that was against the rules!
卡尔文
Calvin.
我忘了跟你说
I forgot to tell you.
你妈妈说她要教我烤馅饼
Your mom said that she was gonna teach me how to bake a pie.
她说我们可以亲手去花园里摘浆果
She says we can just go out in the garden and pick the berries ourselves.
很棒是不是？
Isn't that amazing?
她以前不这样
She didn't used to be like this.
不怎样？
Like what?
老爸在世的时候，她不在意仪表，喜欢操持家务
When Dad was around, she wore polo shirts and cooked meat.
现在她就像被洗过脑一样
It's like she's been brainwashed.
我觉得她和莫特看起来真的很幸福
I think she and Mort seem really happy.
卡尔文
Calvin!
- 小心 - 快下来
- Watch out! - Come on!
- 快下来 - 卡尔文
- Come down here! - Hey, Calvin!
卡尔文，卡尔文
Calvin! Calvin!
- 开始跳 - 小心
- Let's go! - Watch out!
- 这池子真是爽啊，兄弟，一起来玩 - 太美了
- The water's great, man, come on. - It's beautiful!
不，谢谢
No, thanks.
太好玩了，不来可就没机会了
Oh, it's so fun.You're missing out.
我答应兰登要把他的书看完
I promised Langdon I'd finish his book.
你为什么不上来陪陪我呢？
Why don't you come up here with me?
好吧，你随意！
Okay, enjoy yourself!
莫特，小心点儿
Mort, be careful.
行星撞地球！
Asteroid!
跳的真不错
That was beautiful.
我们仨一起跳，一起跳
Now do it with me. Do it with me.
卡尔文，宝贝？
Calvin, honey?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我没事儿
Yeah. I'm fine.
好吧
Okay.
你带她来这儿我真高兴
I'm really glad you brought her.
这对我意义重大
It means a lot to me.
好吧
Okay.
半小时后吃晚饭
Dinner's in a half hour.
哈利，哈利，哈利
But, hey, Harry, Harry, Harry.
- 你想不想看我的史考特表情？ - 想
- You wanna see my impression of Scotty? - Yeah.
一看我就笑
That makes me laugh.
想看我表演史考特生气的表情吗？
Wanna see my impression of Scotty when he's really angry?
想
Yeah.
太不像了
That's so wrong.
他像个知识分子
He's an intellectual.
那样不错
Oh, that is good.
别拿史考特开玩笑
Uh, don't make fun of Scotty.
别激动
Oh, calm down.
- 来，尝一口 - 我的天哪，你看起来真可爱
- Hey, come on. Take it. - Oh, my God. You look so cute here.
- 真是经典 - 我说过我不想要
- That was such a classic. - I told you I don't want it.
- 你应该试试，挺醇的 - 没事儿，他不需要这些
- You should try it. It's really mellow. - It's all right. He doesn't need it.
- 他的思想够强大了 - 是，很强大
- His brain is big enough. - Yeah, no, it's big.
强大到，他能…
It's so big, he can...
只是运用想象力，他就能…他想着
Just with his thoughts, he can just... He thinks it and:
- 哈利 - 就…
- Harry? - Just...
- 就… - 宝贝儿，别这么控制狂了
- Just... - Honey, not here.
一个想法，我是说，他就能，砰
One thought.I mean, he just can just, poof.
- 他就，砰 - 哈利，我认为你喝得够多了
- He just, poof. - Harry, I think you've had enough.
- 你说什么呢？ - 说我爱你呀
- What are you talking about? - I'm talking about I love you.
- 什么？ - 有人得去睡了
- What? - Yay, someone is ready for bed.
- 恩，我真的得睡了 - 我们走
- Yeah, I'm definitely ready. - Let's go.
晚餐很赞
Well, this was a great dinner.
- 我来…我来帮你 - 你知道吗？莫特
- Here, let me... Let me help you. - You know what, Mort?
我觉得你做的够多了
I think you've done plenty.
- 好吧，晚安 - 好的，好的
- Yeah. Good night. - Great, great.
- 你还好吗？ - 好，你呢？
- You okay? - Yeah, you okay?
- 走 - 我很好
- Go. - I'm fine.
大索尔，各位
Big Sur, everybody.
- 走吧，疯子 - 我喜欢这地方，我爱你们
- Come on, crazy. - I love this place. Love you.
我得进去和他谈谈
I think I'm gonna go inside and, uh, talk to him.
好
Okay.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
没事儿
No, it's okay.
只要他不是一直这样
As long as I know he isn't like this all the time.
他不是
He isn't.
好吧
Good.
看
Look.
- 那是你吗？ - 是啊
- Is that you? - Heh, yes.
旁边的是杰克
And that was Jack.
他真帅
He's so handsome.
恩，不苟言笑，卡尔文也那样
Yes, and very, very serious, just like Calvin.
- 他是高尔夫选手吗？ - 露比
- He was a golfer? - Ruby?
- 什么事儿？ - 露比，去睡觉
- Wha...? Hey. - Ruby, bed.
- 现在吗？ - 是
- Right now? - Yes.
你为什么不要呢？
Why won't you take it?
我想你接受它
I want you to have it.
- 出什么事儿了？ - 卡尔文不要我的礼物
- What's going on? - Calvin won't accept my present.
为什么不呢
Why not?
- 莫特的家具做得很用心 - 是啊
- Mort works hard on his furniture. - Yeah.
- 我叫它“孤松椅” - 好美的名字
I call it the Lone Pine. That's beautiful.
- 你不喜欢吗？ - 他当然喜欢，这椅子这么棒
- Don't you like it? - Of course he does. It's a great chair.
过来坐坐，感受感受
Come on, sit down, sit down. Just feel the wood.
卡尔文
Calvin...
♪Skinnamarinky dinky dink♪ （无特定含义，类似国内的绕口令，本身是童谣，主要是为了表达对妈妈的爱）
♪Dinky do♪ （Lyrics by	 Felix A. Feist）
【Source The Echo (musical)】 #我爱你
I love you
♪Skinnamarinky dinky dink♪
♪Dinky do♪
#我爱你
I love you
#我爱你不分早晚
I love you in the morning And in the afternoon
亲爱的，我正在看书
Honey, I'm trying to read.
露比
Ruby?
整个周末你都在看该死的书
You read your stupid book all weekend.
莫特和你妈妈对你那么用心
Your mom and Mort were trying so hard.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你一个朋友也没有
You don't have any friends.
我有你
I have you.
我不需要别人
I don't need anyone else.
这让我压力很大
That's a lot of pressure.
-  我很寂寞 - 别，别那样说，求你
- I'm so lonely. - No. Don't say that. Please.
我们要怎么做？
What do we do?
怎样才能更好呢？
How do we make it better?
- 也许我可以去上上美术课 - 好啊
- Maybe I could take an art class. - Great.
去上美术课，去外面走一走，这不错
An art class. Get out of the house. It's good.
我想我该再回自己家呆几天
And I think I should start spending some nights at my apartment again.
你家吗？
Your apartment?
一周呆一晚
One night a week.
就当做个试验
As an experiment.
好
Okay.
史考特，过来
Hi, Scotty. Come here.
老师真的很棒
The teacher's just amazing.
虽然这些人年纪一大把了，可天赋很高
It's kind of an older group,but the talent level's really high.
我觉得我会学到很多东西
I think I'm gonna learn a lot.
- 昨晚过得怎么样？ - 糟透了
- How was your night? - Terrible.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我觉得这试验不适合我
I don't think this experiment is gonna work for me.
恋人得有各自的空间
There has to be space in the relationship.
否则我们就没有任何区别了
Otherwise, it's like we're the same person.
一周一晚而已，我觉得你能搞定
Listen, it's one night a week.I think you can handle it.
我得去洗个澡
I've gotta take a shower.
宝贝儿，过来
Come on, baby.
你好？
Hello?
- 你好 - 好，你在哪儿呢？
- Hi. - Hi. Where are you?
班上的一些同学决定出去玩，我们在酒吧呢
Um, a bunch of people from class decided to go out, so we're at this bar.
你什么时候回家？
When you coming home?
不知道，我们刚到
I don't know. We just got here.
我做了饭
I cooked.
抱歉，我不回了，我们打算在这儿吃
Sorry, no. You know,I think that we're just gonna eat here.
餐已经点好了，所以…
I mean, we already ordered, so...
那你什么时候回家呢？
So when are you coming home?
不知道，你家离这儿有些远，我们正喝着酒呢，所以…
I don't know. Your place is kind of far and we're drinking, so...
我可能会玩得有点晚
You know, I might be kind of late.
不如我们明天见吧
Why don't we just see each other tomorrow?
- 卡尔文？ - 在
- Calvin? - Yeah.
好吧，好好玩
Okay. Um, have a great time.
没有卡尔文，露比痛不欲生
卡尔文，我想回家
Calvin, I wanna come home.
- 不要 - 我得去尿尿
- No. - I have to pee.
陪我
Stay.
我现在好想你
I miss you right now.
卡尔文
Oh, Calvin.
- 我不想谈那个 - 抱歉
- I'd rather not talk about it. - I'm sorry.
【情归巴黎Sabrina-1954】 我一直以为你是独行侠
I always thought you walked alone.
没有人愿意孤独一生
No man walks alone from choice.
- 你去哪儿？ - 接电话
- Where are you going? - To get the phone.
我能一起去吗？
Can I come with you?
两张七点四十五的票
Two for the 7:45.
售完了，九点有一场
It's sold out. There's a 9:00.
先去散散步吧
Take a walk first?
两张九点的票
Two for the 9.
看这个
Look at this.
你好？
Hello?
你可算接电话了
Look who answered their phone.
塞勒斯，抱歉，最近一直忙
Cyrus, hey. Sorry, I've been busy.
- 没事，孩子，忙着写书吗？ - 对啊
- No worries, man. Busy writing? - Uh, yeah.
是吗？太好了，我一直跟他们说你在写东西
Yeah? Good, that's great. I keep telling them you're working on it.
出版商担心新书…
The publishers are getting anxious about the new book...
对，新书
Right, the new book.
- 前段时间你对新书很激动… - 我在外面呢
- You seemed excited about it a while back... - I'm out right now...
有没有新进展？我能给他们大概的完成时间吗？
Any progress since then? Can I give them some time line...?
- 塞勒斯，待会儿打给你 - 什么？
- Cyrus, I'm gonna call you back. - What?
露比
Ruby?
Ruby!
出什么事了？我转身你就消失了
Hey. Hey, hey. What happened? I turned around and you were gone.
- 你松开了我的手 - 我…什么？
- You let go of my hand. - I... What?
你松开了我的手
You let go of my hand.
什么？我得接电话啊
What...? I had to pick up the phone.
- 我知道，但你松手了 - 露比
- I know, but you let go. - Ruby.
你都没发现我不见了
You didn't even notice I was gone.
露比
Ruby.
宝贝儿，别哭了
Sweetie, you have to calm down.
- 我去给你倒些水，好不好？ - 不要走
- I'm gonna get you some water, okay? - No.
- 别走 - 我马上回来
- No. - I'll be right back.
露比欣喜若狂
你好呀，小笨蛋
Hi, dummy.
好
Hi.
他在追我，不要啊
Aah, he's chasing me.No.
迈尔斯，耶，迈尔斯
Miles. Yay, Miles.
- 谢谢 - 他是个水宝宝呀
- Thanks. - He's a water baby.
- 能问你些事吗？ - 我来抓你啦
- Can I ask something? - I'm coming to get you.
问吧
Shoot.
- 如果我说我又开始写了，你会怎么想？ - 不要呀，他踢我
- What if I told you I was writing again? - Oh, no, he kicked me.
很棒啊
Hey, that's fantastic.
写了些什么？
What's it about?
开始写她了
Writing again.
就这样，喵喵喵
All right! Meow! Meow! Meow!
- 你好 - 怎么样？
- Oh. Hi. - How's it going?
很好
Good.
- 关于她的胸？ - 不是
- Her tits? - No.
她不快乐
She wasn't happy.
- 我使她快乐 - 我是皇后
- So I made her happy... - I'm a queen!
于是她就一直这么傻呵呵的乐着
...and now she's like this all the time.
你想问我什么呢？道不道德吗？我不知道
What are you asking me?If it's moral? I don't know.
这么做显然有效
It's obviously working.
就当它是百忧解吧[治疗精神抑郁的药]
Think of it like Prozac.
- 但我怎样才能知道她是不是真快乐呢？ - 假的，明白吗？她不是真的快乐
- But how do I know it's real? - It's not, okay? She's not.
她现在…她曾经快乐过
She i... She was.
不要呀
Oh, no.
- 我想让她真正快乐起来 - 我爱你呀，小宝贝
- I want to be what's making her happy... - I love you, baby.
而不是把她写的很快乐
...without making her happy.
那就写露比回到了平常的样子，没什么大不了
So write "Ruby went back to normal." No big deal.
我是一只小小狗，快乐水中游呀
I'm a puppy dog swimming in the water.
之前我以为她会离开我
I think she was gonna leave me before.
救命，救命
Help. Help.
苏西离开过一次
Susie left once.
什么时候？为什么你没告诉我？
When? Why didn't you tell me?
你当时很忙
You had a lot going on.
后来她回来了
And she came back.
但我仍然想着这事儿
But I still think about it.
我随时可能失去她
I could lose her any moment.
踩到裂缝，你妈背痛 【这是一种美国人视为“运气不好”的迷信，只使用在孩子身上】
Step on a crack, break your mother's back.
我在考虑离开几个月
I'm thinking about going away for a few months.
- 就我自己 - 你要去哪儿？
- By myself. - Where do you wanna go?
还没定，远点的地方
I don't know.Um, somewhere far.
你可以给我寄明信片，我可喜欢收信了
You could send me postcards.I love getting mail.
要不就躲屋里哪儿也不去
Or I might hole up here in the house, not even go outside.
酷啊
Cool.
我们可以用枕头搭个堡垒
We could build a pillow fort.
露比就是露比，无论快乐或者悲伤
这里是你们证明自己的舞台，米歇尔，从你开始
This is your proving ground. Start with you, Michelle.
- 好吧 - 你的步态优美
- Yes. - You have a superior walk.
- T台上定有你的一席之地，但… - 谢谢
- I can see you doing runway, but... - Thank you.
你干嘛呢，我们得去参加兰登的派对
What are you doing?We have Langdon's party.
- 谁？ - 兰登·夏普
- Who? - Langdon Tharp.
- 那个作家，今晚是他的新书派对 - 嘿，我正看着呢
- The writer. His book party's tonight. - Hey, I was watching that.
- 对啊，看了好几天了 - 这是连播节目
- Yeah, for days. - It's a marathon.
以前你一直让我拟定计划，我照做了
You were always asking me to make plans for us. I did.
别拿我说过的话来压我，我有权改变想法
Don't quote me to myself.I am allowed to change my mind.
- 我不想为这个吵架 - 好，太好了，就这么忽略吧
- I don't want to fight about this. - Fine, great! Let's ignore it, then.
看看席拉，席拉的装扮与众不同
Now look at Sheila.Sheila has such a unique look.
非常棒，这点大家有目共睹
And I think that's wonderful. We've all noticed it.
我们喜欢你的活力
We love your energy.
莎莉蓬松高发髻很有趣 【流行于1970年代，如Goldie Hawn在电影There's a Girl in Your Soup】
Sally made a really interesting choice using that big tease...
但有些太过了
...but it was too much.
她真够大胆的
She's not afraid to be bold.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你知道吗？最近起伏太大
Everything's been so up and down lately, you know?
我很迷茫
It's like my internal compass is just gone.
或许我应该找人谈谈
Maybe I should talk to someone.
你之前看过心理医生吧？
You used to see someone, didn't you?
是，罗森塔尔医生
Uh, Dr. Rosenthal.
也许你该再去找找他
Maybe you should go back.
我们不是在说你吗？
I thought we were talking about you.
是啊，是啊，是说我
Yeah, yeah, we are.
也许你说得对，也许我需要出去走走
Maybe you're right. Maybe I just need to get out.
见见陌生人，交交朋友
See people. Be social.
派对会很有意思
This party's gonna be fun.
兰登，你好，兰登
Langdon. Hey, Langdon, hey.
欢迎来到我的圈子
Welcome to my cult.
- 尔，你得去跟亚当和曼迪谈谈 - 谁？
- Cal, you have to talk to Adam and Mandi. - Who?
亚当和曼迪，想买你的书版权的制作人
Adam and Mandi. The producers ho wanna take over your option.
- 托你看看短信吧 - 塞勒斯，这是露比
- Please, check your messages. - Cyrus, this is Ruby.
- 你好 - 露比
- Hi.  -Ruby
我是塞勒斯，见到你很高兴
Cyrus. Nice.
- 这位是莎斯姬亚 - 你好
- This is Saskia. - Hi.
- 好了，走吧 - 你好
- Okay. Come. - Hi.
呆这儿，我马上回来
Stay there, I'll be right back.
你想亲自来写剧本吗？
You wanna write he screenplay yourself?
那是当然，不然谁来写？
Oh, of course. Yes, absolutely. Who else would?
我不知道，我没写过剧本
I don't know. I've never written one.
神呐，你真是天才，对你来说没问题
My God, you're such a genius, you'd pick it up like that.
我一直这么叫他，他不喜欢别人叫他天才
I've been telling him that. He doesn't like that word.
你想让谁来演查理？
Who'd you wanna play Charlie?
- 那才是问题所在，是吧？ - 对啊
- I mean, that's the question, right? - Yeah.
有空你该来找我谈谈这事儿
You should come and talk to me about it sometime.
现在亚当和曼迪和我们分享他们在纪录片领域的经验
Now, Adam and Mandi come in with  experience from  dumentary films.
他们接触的都是可信的，他们拍的很真实
Everything they touch is authentic.They make it real.
- 基于现实… - 对于叙事我们也保证其真实性…
- Grounded in reality and... - We treat narrative the exact same way...
- 看过他们的那部婴儿纪录片了吧 - 看过
- You saw the baby documentary they did. - Yes.
- 不错，拍得棒极了 - 看的我都想要孩子了
- Okay. Genius. - Made me wanna have a kid.
你不知道有多少人说过同样的话
You have no idea how many people told us the same thing.
- 这是对的 - 你能拿一会儿吗？
- Well, it's true. - Can you hold this just for a second?
- 抱歉，我离开一会儿 - 好，你去吧
- No, sorry, I'll be right back. - Yeah, absolutely.
- 很高兴能和你谈话 - 好
- Great to talk to you. - Okay.
- 一会儿再谈 - 好
- Talk to you in a bit. - Okay.
- 待会儿见 - 好
- See you later. - Okay.
抱歉，对不起
Excuse me. Sorry.
- 卡尔 - 莱拉
- Cal. - Lila.
我以为你在纽约
I thought you were in New York.
没，兰登正在帮我出版小说
Uh, no, Landgon's helping me publish my novel.
你的小说写完了啊
You finished your novel.
这算是个大惊喜吧，半吊子居然写完了一本书，是吧？
I know, it's a big surprise, the, uh... The dilettante finished something, right?
我没说过那样的话
I never said that.
- 你呢？现在在写东西吗？ - 当然
- What about you? Are you writing? - Sure.
好，那很好
Good. Great.
- 听说你交女朋友了 - 嗯，她在这儿
- I hear you're seeing someone? - Yeah. She's here.
借过
Excuse me.
- 她是作家吗？ - 不是
- Is she a writer? - No.
不是，她是个画家
No, a painter.
真好，这样她对你就不构成威胁了
That's great.It's very, um, unthreatening.
你认为你的作家身份威胁到我了吗？
You think I was threatened by you?
没有，怎么会呢，你是个天才
No, Cal, why would you be?You're a genius.
你喜欢我的泳池吗？
You like my pool?
- 我见过你吗？ - 我想没有
- Do I know you? - I don't think so.
你来我的派对干什么？
What are you doing at my party?
你告诉我吧
You tell me.
你是和别人一起来的吗？
You come with someone?
卡尔文·威尔·菲尔兹
Calvin Weir-Fields.
啊，天才少年
Ah, the boy wonder.
你是只和著名作家约会的那类女孩儿吗？
So are you one of those girls who only dates famous writers?
为什么这么说？你是著名作家吗？
Why? Are you a famous writer?
请问你的名字？
Do you happen to have a name?
- 露比 - 露比
- Ruby. - Ruby.
露比，你的职业是？
And what do you do, Ruby?
自由职业
Nothing.
真新鲜的回答，那你空闲时间都做些什么呢？
How refreshing.What do you do in your spare time?
没什么活动
Not much.
我刚才一直在想，一直在想…
You know, I was thinking,I was just thinking...
今晚真是适合畅游呢
...tonight would be perfect for a swim
我没带泳衣
I don't have a suit.
那算是个问题吗？
Is that a problem?
无所谓，不知道为什么我觉得你会替我感到高兴
Never mind. I don't know why I thought maybe you'd be happy for me.
为什么你会觉得我不支持你呢？
How was I anything but supportive?
我看了你给我的每一篇底稿，我带你进入我的社交圈
I read every draft you gave me. I took you into my group.
- 我把你介绍给了兰登 - 并非自愿
- I introduced you to Langdon. - Begrudgingly.
- 什么？我听不见你在说什么 - 你并非自愿
- What? I literally can't hear you. - Begrudgingly.
你压根儿对我没兴趣，没有
You weren't curious about me. You never were.
你对我一直有偏见
You just had this image of who I was.
而我做的挽回的举动，你都视而不见
And anything that I did that contradicted it, you just ignored.
什么偏见？我不出名了你马上就抛弃了我？
What image?The one Where you left me as soon as I wasn't successful?
你认为我在乎你的名声吗？
You think I gave a shit if you were famous?
我想要的不过是你的关心
All that I wanted was for you,I don't know, to care about me.
关心你吗？我爸去世没几周你就离开我了
Care about you?You left weeks after my father died.
- 你真想谈谈关心这回事儿吗？ - 我的上帝
- Do you wanna talk about caring? - Oh, God.
- 你知道别人怎么说的吗？ - 你真是不可理喻
- Do you know what people say? - You were impenetrable.
- 你怎么会爱上那种女人？ - 我试着去帮助你
- "How could you love that person?" - I tried to help.
- 你不让我走进你的内心 - 我只能说“我他妈也不知道！”
- You refused to let me in. - And I say, "I have no fucking clue!"
只想和你自己谈恋爱
The only person that you wanted to be in a relationship with was you.
所以我如你所愿
So I let you do that.
你真是把自己撇的一干二净，对吗？
You really let yourself off the hook,don't you?
- 拜，卡尔 - 拜拜
- Goodbye, Cal. - Goodbye.
祝你生活愉快
Have a great life.
来吧，水温暖宜人，游过来吧
Come on.It's nice and warm. Swim to me.
如果不想脱你可以穿着内衣裤
You can keep your underwear on if you like.
快来吧
Come on in.
- 不准偷看 - 好，我保证不偷看
- No peeking. - All right, I promise, I won't peek.
好吧
All right.
神呐
Oh, boy.
写作是感性的，这…
Writing is sensual. It's, uh...
你该看看我写作时的样子，就像奥林匹斯众神
You should see me when I write.I'm like an Olympian.
- 真的吗？ - 我挥舞着手中的笔…
- Oh, really? - I wield my pen...
- 你的笔吗？ - 像一把光剑
- Your pen? - ...like a lightsaber.
- 你们在干什么？ - 卡尔文
- What's going on here? - Calvin.
我们，我们就在池子里泡泡
We, uh... We thought we'd take a dip.
要不要一起来？
Care to join us?
- 怎么会那样？ - 什么？
- What was that? - What was what?
- 你知道我在说什么 - 别大惊小怪
- You know what. - Grow up.
史考特
Scotty.
- 嘿 - 嘿，你弄疼我了
- Hey. - Hey! You're hurting me.
解释下你刚才在干什么
Explain what you were doing.
你把我扔到了一个全是陌生人的派对
You left me alone at a party where I didn't know anyone.
- 我找了个能说话的人 - 只穿着你的内衣
- I found someone to talk to. - In your underwear.
以前我穿比基尼的时候你生过气吗？
Would you have been mad if I had been in my bikini?
刚才你穿的不是比基尼
You weren't wearing your bikini.
你知道那看起来像什么吗？
Do you know what it looked like?
我的经纪人在那儿，我的前女友也在
My agent was there.My ex was there.
莱拉也在哪儿？为什么你没告诉我？
Lila was there?Why didn't you tell me?
我当时正忙着让你穿衣服
I was too busy getting you to put your clothes back on.
- 你应该是我的女朋友 - 我是你的女朋友
- You're supposed to be my girlfriend. - I am your girlfriend.
那你就表现得像一点
So act like it.
很抱歉我没能表现得像你的理想情人一样
I'm sorry I wasn't acting like the platonic ideal of your girlfriend.
天啊，你真是反应过度
Jesus, you can be such a fucking prude.
就因为我不想你跟别的男人裸泳？
Beause I don't want you skinny-dipping with men?
因为你什么也不让我做
Because you don't want me doing anything!
你有各种规定，而我全然不知
You have all these rules and you don't tell me what they are...
知道我打破你的规定
...until, whoops,I've broken one.
接着你就对我失望了吗？
And then you get to be disappointed with me?
好，你想知道我的原则吗？
Okay. Uh, do you wanna know my rules?
不要去招惹其他男人，不要让他们对你有意思
Don't fuck other men.Don't let them think about fucking you.
现在我还得对别人的想法负责了吗？
Now I'm responsible for what people think?
对，你得负责，你的行为会影响到他人的行为
Yes, you are responsible. When you act a certain way, it leads people on.
当你在派对上脱光衣服，只会让别人认为你是个荡妇
When you take your clothes off at a party,people think you're a slut.
所以我建议你别那样做，这样说够清楚了吗？
So I'd really prefer if you didn't do that. Is that clear enough for you?
操你！
Fuck you!
我不是你的孩子
I'm not your child!
你没权利支配我的行为
You don't get to decide what I do.
- 想赌一把吗？ - 什么？
- Wanna bet? - What?
我非常肯定我能对你为所欲为
I'm pretty sure I could make you do whatever I want.
卡尔文，你想干什么？把我绑起来吗？
What are you gonna do, Calvin?Tie me up?
不
No.
没这个必要
I don't have to.
卡尔文
Calvin...
我要叫出租车
...I'm gonna call a cab.
我们明天再谈，好吗？
Let's talk tomorrow, okay?
卡尔文
Calvin.
好啊，你走吧
Fine. Go.
怎么回事？
What was that?
你没感觉到吗？
You didn't feel that?
什么东西？
What is that?
该死的到底怎么回事？
What the fuck is going on?
卡尔文
Calvin.
- 我的上帝啊，发生什么事了 - 来，看看这个
- Oh, my God, something is happening. - Here. Read.
这是什么？
What is this?
我的书
My book.
那本我没写完的
The one I haven't been working on.
想看看吗？
Wanna see?
这是你开的玩笑吗？
Is this some sort of joke?
不，很严肃
No. It's pretty serious.
你在写我吗？
You're writing about me?
不，你不能写我，这是隐私
No, you can't write about me.That's private.
现在我没写你
I'm not writing about you.
以前写的
I wrote you.
我创造了你
I made you up.
- 什么？ - 我梦见了一个女孩
- What? - I had a dream about a girl.
于是我就创作了她
So I wrote it down.
我给她起了名字
I gave her a name.
露比
Ruby.
我写了她的各种细节，然后有一天我醒来她…
I wrote all kinds of things about her and then one day I woke up and she...
你就出现在了我家
You were living in my house.
我能支配的你行为
I can make you do anything...
因为你并不真实存在
...because you're not real.
你个变态
You're sick.
卡尔文
Calvin?
听我说
Listen to me.
如果这就是你看待他人的方式
If this is how you think about people...
那你注定孤老终身
...then you are in for a long,lonely, fucked-up life.
你听见我的话了吗？卡尔文？
Do you hear me? Calvin?
我对天发誓，你最好听…
什么--
我在说法语吗？
我根本不会说法语啊
怎么--
看，“露比说法语”
See. "Ruby speaks French."
发生什么事了？
告诉过你我能支配你的行为
I told you I could make you do anything.
这是什么？
我写的
I write it.
但你是怎么做到的？
你就照做了
You do it.
露比用右手打响指
上帝啊
停下来
卡尔文，停下来
露比边唱歌边脱衣服
Skinnamarinky dinky dink dinky do
#我爱你
I love you
Skinnamarinky dinky dink
Dinky do
#我爱你
I love you
#早上我爱你
I love you in the morning
我爱你
I love you.
永伴你左右，我爱你
I'll never leave you. I love you.
不离不弃
I'll never leave you.
我爱你，不离不弃
I love you. I'll never leave you.
我爱你的唇，爱你的鼻子
I love your mouth. I love your nose.
爱你的臀，爱你的眼
I love your butt. I love your eyes.
爱你的腹，爱你的耳
I love your belly. I love your ears.
我爱你的老二，爱你的鼻子
I love your cock. I love your nose.
爱你的唇，我太爱你
I love your mouth. I love you so much.
永远爱你，地老天荒
I'll love you forever and ever and ever and ever.
你是天才，你是天才，你是天才
You're a genius. You're a genius.You're a genius.
You're a genius.You're a genius. You're a genius.
你是天才，你是天才，你是天才
You're a genius. You're a genius.You're a genius.
露…
Rub...
露比离开之后，这里的一切对她而言即成过往
她不再是卡尔文的笔下之物
她自由了
卡尔文
Calvin?
Calvin.
你还好吗？
You okay?
她走了
She's gone.
兄弟，没事的
It's okay, buddy.
不错
Okay.
没什么用
Nothing helps.
- 卡尔，你最后一次写东西是什么时候？ - 我写不出来
- When was the last time you wrote, Cal? - I can't write.
你肯定有故事可写
Sure you can.
那就是你比那些心碎的笨蛋强的地方
That's what you have over every other poor schmuck out there with a broken heart.
你可以把这事儿写下来
You can write about it.
谁会去看呢？
And who would wanna read that?
很多人会
Lots of people.
为什么不看呢？
Why not?
你的经历很神奇
You got a pretty great story.
大家会认为我是个疯子
Everyone will think I'm crazy.
不会
No.
他们会当这是个虚构的故事
They'll think it's fiction.
这就是我那真实而又不可思议的爱情故事
This is the true and impossible story of my very great love.
希望她不会看到这个故事，不会谴责我
In the hope that she will not read this and reproach me...
我隐去了诸多细节
...I have withheld many telling details.
她的名字
Her name...
出身年月和成长经历
...the particulars of her birth and upbringing..
及一切她独有的伤疤和胎记
...and any identifying scars or birthmarks.
尽管如此，我情不自禁为她提笔写下了肺腑之言
All the same,I cannot help but write this for her.
借此告诉她：
To tell her:
我为自己写下的改变你的每一个词感到抱歉
"I'm sorry for every word I wrote to change you.
我对很多事抱歉
I'm sorry for so many things.
你在时我视而不见
I couldn't see you when you were here.
你走了，却如影随形
And now that you're gone,I see you everywhere."
有读者也许会认为这是魔法
"One may read this and think it's magic...
但爱情本就是一种魔法
...but falling in love is an act of magic.
写作亦是
So is writing.
《麦田里的守望者》中曾写道：
It was once said of Catcher in the Rye:
小说里的奇迹再度降临
'That rare miracle of fiction has again come to pass.
笔墨、纸张、和想象力创造出了一个人
A human being has been created out of ink, paper and the imagination.'
我不是J.D塞林格
I am no J.D. Salinger...
但我亲眼目睹了奇迹的诞生
...but I have witnessed a rare miracle.
每一位作家都能切身地体会到
Any writer can attest...
最幸运和快乐的状态
...in the luckiest, happiest state...
是词由心生
...the words are not coming from you,but through you.
她找到了我
She came to me wholly herself.
曾经拥有她是我最大的幸运
I was just lucky enough to be there to catch her."
谢谢各位
Thank you.
他的想象力是不是叹为观止？
Doesn't his imagination just,uh, blow you away?
是说，他到底是怎么得到这些灵感的啊？
I mean, where does he come up with these ideas?
- 对不对？ - 是啊
- Right? - Yeah.
- 天才 - 我不清楚
- Genius. - I don't know.
我不知道
I don't know.
- 最近怎么样？ - 近来可好？
- How are you? - What's up?
卡尔文，故事很美
It's beautiful, Calvin.
谢谢
Thank you.
大多数病人不会这么认真地对待我布置的作业
Most of my patients don't take my assignments this seriously.
我知道你希望我写完这本书后，能意识到这一切从未发生过
I know you hoped that, by writing this,I would realize that it never happened.
她只是我想象的
That I imagined her.
但事实是…
But the thing is...
我不需要解释这一切
...I don't need to make sense of this.
我不在乎对此是否有合理的解释
I don't care if there's no good explanation.
无论如何，请你相信我
I need you to believe me anyway.
请尝试一下
Just take the leap.
为了我
At least imagine how it could be true.
就认为它是真的吧
For me.
我会试试的
I'll work on that.
快尿尿
Go potty.
史考特，史考特
Scotty. Scotty.
史考特
Scotty.
- 你好 - 抱歉
- Oh, hi. - Sorry.
- 你好 - 抱歉，它是我的狗
- Hi. - Sorry, he's mine.
没事儿，它很温顺
It's fine. He's so friendly.
- 怎么称呼它？ - 史考特
- What's his name? - Scotty.
史考特，真有趣，那…
Scotty. That's funny, that's...
和这本书里的狗同名
That's the name of the dog in this book.
你读过这本书了吗？
Have you read it?
喜欢吗？
Did you like it?
抱歉，你刚才说什么了吗？
Sorry. Did you say something?
是，我问你喜不喜欢这书
Yeah, I just asked if you liked it.
你觉得怎么样？
Uh, what did you think?
借我这本书的朋友觉得这书很矫情…
My friend who lent it to me thought it was kind of pretentious...
反正目前我很喜欢
...but I really like it so far.
我们见过吗？
Have we met before?
我不知道
I don't know.
你看起来很眼熟
You seem really familiar.
也许我们上辈子见过
Maybe we knew each other in another life.
或者我们只是去过同一家咖啡店
Or maybe we just go to the same coffee shop.
除了遛狗你都做些什么呢？
What do you do besides go for walks with your dog?
我是个作家
I'm a writer.
你写些什么呢？
What do you write?
难怪你看起来很眼熟
So that's why you look so familiar.
也许吧
Maybe.
朋友说你的书很矫情是我开的玩笑
I was kidding about my friend calling it pretentious.
没事
It's okay.
我们能重新开始吗？
Can we start over?
好啊
Yes.
- 我能坐下吗？ - 当然，请坐
- May I sit down? - Oh, please.
别告诉我结局好吗？
Just don't tell me how it ends, okay?
没问题
Promise.